Michael Peterson

 ♥ Bordentown, NJ
 ⋈ michaelgordanpeterson@gmail.com
 ੑ (609) 954-5900

in michaelgpeterson

Summary .

Software developer with 7 years of experience, specializing in React with additional strengths in backend development. Skilled at building intuitive and responsive user interfaces. Self-directed and committed to continuously innovating solutions, as well as improving processes across the stack.

Technologies ____

Skills: Javascript/Typescript, React, Node.js, Google Cloud Platform, SQL (PostgreSQL, MariaDB), Git, HTML/CSS

Experience ____

Infinite Blue, Software Engineer

- Developed, updated, and maintained key components of an enterprise resilience application, working with multiple microservices and micro frontends; done primarily through utilizing React, Node, Pulsar, PostgreSQL, and GraphQL. These components streamlined and enhanced business responses to catastrophic events, ensuring robust and efficient disaster management.
- Implemented algorithm to cluster business threats, utilizing pub/sub to generate and store threat data in a database; data was accessed via API and visually represented on a map using React, providing a clear, actionable view of potential threats.
- · Created REST API delta endpoint, significantly increasing upload speed for bulk data submitted by customers.
- Archived critical data using Node and SQL queries, meeting contractual obligations and enabling the generation of reports that provided customers with valuable insights into threats to their company and allowed them to access unique threat data for future analysis.

Onepak, Software Developer

- Implemented a new B2C application, taking it from concept to MVP employing React. Zeplin was utilized as a key tool to work with mockups, ensuring pixel-perfect implementation of the design elements and maintaining a cohesive user interface.
- Maintained and optimized logistical software for multiple B2B applications responsible for recycling technological equipment for industry leaders such as Dell and Hewlett Packard.
- Collaborated closely with design and marketing teams, translating their vision and requirements into a functional and visually appealing application.

Implico, Software Developer

- Designed, implemented, and maintained a suite of applications for internal use utilizing the PERN stack at Sam's Club, critical to the everyday operations in the fuels division implementation of the design elements and maintaining a cohesive user interface.
- Created iOS/Android mobile application to accompany software suite, nationally utilized by truck drivers to assist with pickup and deliveries.
- Produced series of SAP Fiori front end applications using SAP Web IDE to track and maintain master data tables and configuration.
- Implemented SSH and IPsec configuration to update fuel measurements of Sam's Club stations, essential to forecasting and fuel tracking.

Audobon, PA 2023 - 2024 1 year

Boston, MA 2022 - 20231 year

Blue Bell, PA 2018 - 2022 4 years

- Completed front end overhaul of receipt tracking application used by companies such as Walmart and Phillips 66.
- Constructed interface utilizing Express.js to interact with SAP and Suncor Energy systems responsible for managing day-to-day fuel logistics

Education _____

Flatiron School, Software Engineering Rigorous bootcamp program teaching students software engineering.	2017 – 2017
New Jersey Institute of Technology, Mechanical Engineering	2016 - 2018
Temple University, History	2011 - 2015